(competition in life)
（較量人生）
(The characters, events, groups, organizations and backgrounds of this drama are purely fictitious. We hereby inform you that)
（本劇之人物、事件、團體、組織 及背景等，純屬虛構，特此告知）
It is expected that there will be about 50 people and the server will not be overloaded, right?
預計會有50個人左右 伺服器不會負荷過重吧？
50 people is nothing at all
50個人根本不算什麼
- Really? - right
- 真的嗎？ - 對
If the opportunity is lost, something big will happen.
要是當機真的會出大事
It won't be a problem, right
不會有問題的，對
- So far - Yes
- 照目前看來 - 是
These look fine
這些看起來也沒問題
Dating?
約會？
Yeah, he asked her if she wanted to go on a date with him
對啊，他問她願不願意跟他約會
I think this is what is called American style
我想這就是所謂的美式作風
Right?
對吧？
"Do you want to date me?", right?
“你想跟我約會嗎？”，沒錯吧？
Then what?
然後呢？
How would Yun Zhao answer?
那允昭怎麼回答？
I don't know, I didn't hear her answer
不知道，我沒聽到她的回答
Do you have something to say to me? Team Leader Liu
你有話要對我說嗎？柳組長
- What? - You've been staring at me since just now
- 什麼？ - 你從剛才就一直盯著我看
me?
我嗎？
No, I wasn't looking at you, I wasn't staring at her
沒有，我才沒看你，我沒有盯著她看
I didn't look at her, how could I stare...
我沒有看她，我怎麼可能盯…
Nevermind
沒有就算了
I thought you were interested in me
我還以為你對我有興趣
Interested…
有興…
you said I? I'm not crazy...
你說我？我又不是瘋…
No, who is interested in you?
才沒有，誰對你有興趣啊？
Absolutely not
絕對沒有
I was joking
我是開玩笑的
Because everyone seems to be too nervous
因為大家好像都太緊張了
I just want to make you laugh
我只是想逗你們笑
Why are you so serious?
你幹嘛那麼嚴肅啊？
It makes me feel a little uncomfortable
害我有點不是滋味
I mean, it’s too much. What’s wrong with Agent Park?
就是說啊，太過分了 朴代理哪裡不好？
Team Leader Liu’s eyes were originally on the top of his head.
柳組長的眼睛本來就長在頭頂上
Agent Park, ignore him. There are many men better than him in the world.
朴代理，別理他 天底下比他好的男人多得是
Okay, start in five minutes
好，五分鐘後開始
Countdown to five seconds
倒數五秒
(Producer Shixiang, Shiyong, I want to know...)
（世想製作人、世容，想知道…）
(Sexiang Planning I, Shixiang Planning II Project Team)
（世想企劃一、世想企劃二 世容專案小組）
(Don’t waste your efforts, four years of experience)
（別白費力氣，年資四年）
"Don't waste your efforts", welcome to you
“別白費力氣”，歡迎你
Can you hear me?
聽得到我說話嗎？
Yes, you can hear it
是，聽得到
This meeting is to discuss matters related to Se Yong, right?
這場會議是用來討論 世容的相關事宜，對嗎？
Yes, that's right
對，沒錯
(Employee of Serong, with three years of experience. The resignation letter in my arms, with five years of experience)
（世容員工，年資三年 我懷中的辭呈，年資五年）
Yes, can you hear me?
是，聽得到嗎？
Hello? There is sound now
喂？現在有聲音了
- hello- hello
- 你們好 - 你好
Hello everyone
大家好
- This one only hears sounds, right? - I think it is
- 這個只聽得到聲音，對吧？ - 我想應該是
- Yeah, that's right - because you can't show your face.
- 對，沒錯 - 因為不能露臉
Is it okay to express dissatisfaction directly?
直接說出不滿也行嗎？
- Please mute everyone - We are going to discuss Se Yong’s affairs today, right?
- 請將全體調成靜音 - 今天是要討論世容的事吧？
- Right? Okay - That's it
- 對吧？好 - 這樣啊
- No need to show your face - Is there no one to chair the meeting?
- 可以不用露臉 - 沒有人主持會議嗎？
If you show your face...
露臉的話…
Dear Shiyong employees
各位世容的員工
Because if multiple people are talking at the same time, the content will not be heard clearly.
因為多人同時講話的話 會聽不太清楚內容
Please write your nickname in the dialog box and we will let you speak in order.
請在對話框寫下自己的暱稱 我們會按順序讓你們發言
(Don’t waste your efforts, four years of experience)
（別白費力氣，年資四年）
(unmute request)
（解除靜音要求）
OK, cleared
好，解除了
Can I speak now?
我可以發言了吧？
As far as I'm concerned
就我看來
Serong’s evaluation mechanism is the biggest problem
世容的評鑑機制才是最大的問題
Let the team leader evaluate all team members unilaterally
讓組長單方面對所有組員進行評鑑
But the evaluation criteria are not transparent enough
但評鑑標準卻不夠透明
(The resignation letter in my arms has five years of experience. I love Shirong and has two years of experience.)
（我懷中的辭呈，年資五年 我愛世容，年資兩年）
(Everyone go away, seven years of experience)
（全都滾開，年資七年）
As long as the person is on the promotion list, the team leader will definitely give S
只要是升遷名單上的人 組長一定會給S
The remaining people will divide A, B and C equally.
剩下的人則平分A、B、C
But there are seniors in each group , so the junior with the least qualifications must get a C
但每組都有前輩在 所以資歷最淺的後輩一定是拿C
In this case, what is the significance of the evaluation system?
既然如此，評鑑制度的意義何在？
Is it necessary to use relative evaluation?
一定要採用相對評鑑的方式嗎？
Yes, please speak next. "Everyone go away, seven years of experience."
是，請下一位發言 “全都滾開，年資七年”
I don't mind showing my face
我不介意露臉
is that OK?
沒問題吧？
(It’s so strong, she actually turned on the camera?)
（太強了，她竟然開鏡頭？）
(amazing, oh my god)
（了不起，天啊）
After I gave birth to my child and returned to work after taking maternity leave , I found out that I had been transferred to another team.
等我生完孩子，休完產假 回工作崗位時卻發現被調組了
Still a dispensable group
還是個可有可無的組別
All the job experience I have accumulated in the past has become useless
我過去累積的所有職務經驗 全都變得毫無用武之地
Doesn't this mean you want me to submit my resignation?
這不就是要我遞辭呈的意思嗎？
(Super handsome! Killed with one hit, like)
（超帥！簡直一擊斃命，讚）
"Everyone go away, seven years of experience" Thank you for your opinion
“全都滾開，年資七年” 謝謝你的意見
The next person is "Hello, three years of experience."
下一位是“你好，年資三年”
- It's over 50 now. - Really?
- 現在超過50位了 - 真的嗎？
Oh, that's ok
喔，可以了
- Isn’t our goal 100? - I am the junior who got C
- 我們的目標不是100位嗎？ - 我就是拿到C的後輩
-Honestly- Yeah, dream goal.
- 老實說 - 對，夢想目標
The team leaders are really not doing anything.
組長們真的都沒在做事
How come everyone is willing to participate when the weather is so nice ?
天氣這麼好 大家怎麼會願意參加啊？
They only know how to chat and do online shopping, but we do all the work
他們只會聊天跟網購 工作都是我們在做
- So unfair - The dialog box is now blocked.
- 太不公平了 - 現在對話框被塞爆了
How to do this?
這該怎麼辦？
Okay, the next one is "No matter what, I will still be Shirong, with ten years of experience."
好，下一位是 “再怎樣都是世容，年資十年”
(At least Shirong has ten years of experience...)
（至少世容，年資十…）
Microphone test…
麥克風測試…
At least the annual salary given by Shi Rong should be considered high, right?
至少世容給的年薪應該算高吧？
There are actually many advantages
優點其實也不少
Everyone said it too much
大家說得太過分了
Aren’t the systems of every company similar?
每間公司的制度不是都差不多嗎？
At least Se Yong
至少世容
Not a company that fires employees casually
不是一間會隨便開除員工的公司
Say more
多說一點
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
(Is he a senior executive spy? His voice sounds familiar)
（是高階主管間諜嗎？ 他的聲音好耳熟）
(What nonsense is that person talking about?)
（那個人在說什麼鬼話？）
What nonsense? I'm talking human language
什麼鬼話？我說的是人話
(He must be getting money, what are you doing?)
（他一定有收錢，你在搞什麼？）
(I support him, he is amazing)
（我支持他，他真了不起）
(I seem to know who he is! Section Chief Meng Zhejun of the Public Relations Group 2)
（我好像知道他是誰！ 公關二組的孟哲俊科長）
Hello!
喂！
- Hey, how could you... - Oh my God
- 喂，你怎麼能… - 天啊
Got kicked out, you brat.
被踢出去了，你這臭小子
It would be more suspicious to quit like that
像那樣退出才更可疑
You should pretend nothing is wrong and carry on...
你應該裝沒事繼續…
Damn it
真該死
Also, doing gymnastics is really outrageous.
還有，做體操真的太不像話了
To be honest, everyone trains themselves these days
老實說這年頭大家都會自我鍛鍊
There is really no need to do gymnastics in the company
真的沒有必要在公司做體操
Okay, next one is "Let me go home, two years seniority"
好，下一位是 “讓我回家，年資兩年”
Although I knew it before I joined the company
雖然我進公司之前就知道
Large companies often have department dinners
大企業經常會有部門聚餐
But it’s too frequent, right?
但次數也太頻繁了吧
Please ask your company to reduce the number of dinner parties
拜託公司減少聚餐次數
Give us some time for self-development
給我們一點自我開發的時間吧
Only by obtaining high-level diplomas and certificates can you have the chance to be promoted, right?
唯有取得高學歷文憑跟證照 才有機會升遷，不是嗎？
Everyone is changing their nicknames
大家正在修改暱稱
They changed their nickname to what they wanted to say
他們把暱稱改成想說的話了
Please guarantee two years of childcare leave without pay
請保障兩年的育嬰留職停薪假
Just have dinner together once every three months.
聚餐三個月一次就好
Increase bonuses, pay benefits in cash
提高獎金，以現金支付福利金
Interview with the team leader or project leader once a quarter
每季跟組長或專案組長面談一次
Flexible work system, self-disciplined attendance system
彈性工作制、自律出勤制
- As well as shortening working hours - I hope employees’ families will also have exclusive benefits
- 以及縮短工時 - 希望員工家人也有專屬福利
- Please provide self-development project subsidies - Please provide children's tuition subsidies
- 請提供自我開發項目補助 - 請提供子女學費補助
I hope the company can set up another girls’ lounge
希望公司能另設女生休息室
Okay, we have listened carefully to everyone’s opinions.
好的，各位的心聲 我們都有好好聽進去了
So the next one is...
那麼下一位是…
300 people
300個人了
What?
什麼？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
What happened?
怎麼搞的？
Hey, what's going on?
喂，這是怎麼回事？
Shouldn't the machine crash?
該不會當機了吧？
right
對
The server cannot handle the traffic of 300 people online at the same time
伺服器無法承受 300個人同時在線的流量
Didn't you say about 50 people?
你不是說大約50個人嗎？
It's only less than 20 minutes since it started.
現在才開始不到20分鐘耶
I know too, okay?
我也知道好嗎？
- Hey, think of a solution. - Give me some time, wait a minute.
- 喂，快想想辦法啊 - 給我點時間，等一下
It seems that when…
看來是當…
Looks like it crashed
看來是當機了
No chance to sing anymore
沒戲唱了
(The host has ended this meeting)
（主持人已結束此會議）
This is actually better
這樣反而更好
This is not a protest rally. What on earth is it doing? Why do you do such a thing?
這又不是什麼抗議集會 到底在做什麼？幹嘛做這種事啊？
That person just now was the deputy head of the customer service team, right?
剛才那個人是客服組的次長吧？
right
對
There is another person showing his face
露臉的還有另一個人
Do they think the company is their exclusive welfare wishing well?
他們以為公司是 他們專屬的福利許願池嗎？
If they are dissatisfied, they leave, and there is no one to stop them.
不滿就走人啊，又沒人攔他們
- If you're unhappy, you can leave. - No, I won't leave my job.
- 你要是不爽也可以滾蛋 - 不，我不會離職的
Oh, what a pity
唉唷，真可惜
It's over too soon
太快結束了
(The host has ended this meeting)
（主持人已結束此會議）
Just when I wanted to do something, it ended
剛想做點什麼就結束了
It seems that there are still many people ready to come in now
現在似乎還有很多人準備進來
Everyone is asking why they can’t get in
大家都在問為什麼進不去
a complete failure
徹底失敗了
Is it really beyond repair?
真的無法修復嗎？
Yes, no way
對，沒辦法
You have no plans to reopen, right?
你們沒有打算要重開吧？
According to today's situation, it seems that our company's servers cannot bear it.
照今天的情況看來 我們公司的伺服器承受不了
Is there nothing we can do about it in the future?
那以後也沒辦法嗎？
honestly…
坦白說…
There is really no way
的確沒辦法
At least the fact that the number of attendees was unexpectedly large is very encouraging.
至少與會人數出乎意料的多 這點倒是很激勵人心
Let's not get too depressed
我們也別太沮喪了
We didn’t expect so many people to participate , so it’s our fault that we couldn’t respond well.
沒料到會有這麼多人參加 導致應對不及是我們的錯
To be honest, the pre-confirmation of the server is indeed too sloppy.
說實話，伺服器的事前確認 也確實過於馬虎了
It must give people an unprofessional feeling.
想必會給人一種不專業的感覺吧
I finally planned everything but failed to get off to a successful start.
好不容易籌劃好一切 卻沒能有個成功的開始
If I had known this, maybe it would have been better not to do it.
早知如此，說不定不做還比較好
Don't be so pessimistic
不用想得那麼悲觀啦
because that's the case
因為情況就是如此
Everyone has worked hard today
大家今天都辛苦了
Are you leaving?
你要走啦？
Let's go have a drink together
一起去喝一杯嘛
I stopped drinking for a while
我這陣子戒酒了
Why?
為什麼？
You shouldn't really feel uncomfortable somewhere...
你該不會真的哪裡不舒…
I already have an appointment
我已經有約了
You should make an appointment in advance to drink.
喝酒應該要提前約啊
It's a happy Saturday after all
畢竟今天是愉快的星期六
At the same time, does this require a review report?
同期，這需要寫檢討報告嗎？
Just help me analyze the reasons.
你幫忙分析原因就好
It's not your fault, so what kind of review report should you write?
又不是你的錯，寫什麼檢討報告？
Analyze the reasons?
分析原因？
“Seyong’s computer system is too old”
“世容的電算系統過於老舊”
One line will solve it
一行字就能解決了
Do you have an appointment?
你有約了嗎？
Is it a date?
是約會嗎？
Let’s go to the Han River
去漢江吧
Ask Xiaoen to remember to bring a picnic mat
叫小恩記得帶野餐墊
no problem
沒問題
- nice shot!
- 好球！
very good
很好
Speaking of Zheng Shouhuan
說到鄭首煥
I heard he actually jumped over you
聽說他居然跳過你
Go directly to the vice president
直接去找副社長
I'm talking about Serdix
我是說塞爾迪克斯的事
The reason why you made that decision before
你先前之所以做出那種決定
Isn't it because you trust Director Zheng?
不就是因為信任鄭室長嗎？
But he acted like he had done nothing wrong
但他卻表現出一副沒做錯事的樣子
Arrive at the vice president with the solution
拿著解決方案大搖大擺地去找副社長
That plan was still the opinion put forward by Director Goo.
那個方案還是具理事那邊提出的意見
It was you who pushed him to take the position of head of the Strategy Headquarters all along.
一直以來都是你力推他去坐 策略本部長的位子
That's so ungrateful of him.
他那麼做也太忘恩負義了
Even I feel angry
連我都覺得生氣
He is a few years younger than me, but he is always extremely rude to me
他小我幾歲，卻總是對我無禮至極
That brat thinks he's the smartest
那個臭小子以為他自己最聰明
That's right, that's right
就是說啊，沒錯
What if that kind of guy becomes the head of the headquarters?
萬一讓那種傢伙當上本部長
He will attribute his excellence to himself and then be like a wild horse out of control.
他就會歸功於自己的優秀 然後像匹脫韁野馬不受控制
so
所以
Do you want to sit in that seat too?
你也想坐上那個位子嗎？
What?
什麼？
no
不是的
How dare I...
我哪敢…
God, how dare I...
天啊，我怎麼有膽子…
Very good, then just wait and see what happens.
很好，那就靜觀其變吧
Okay, no problem, of course
好，沒問題，那是當然的
Get out of the way
讓開點
Yes, okay
對喔，好的
I also wish you good luck this time.
這次也預祝你打出好球
Okay, be careful on the road, bye
好，路上小心，再見
Xiao En said she was almost there
小恩說她快到了
OK, take it
好，拿去
Thanks
謝啦
cheers
乾杯
- Awesome - It feels so good
- 真棒 - 感覺真好
Hey, do you know?
喂，你知道嗎？
London and Paris also have rivers running through their cities.
倫敦跟巴黎也有河流貫穿市區
But the width is less than 300 meters
但寬度都不到300公尺
Looking back at the Han River
反觀漢江
Nearly 1 km wide
寬度將近1公里
It’s really rare to see a city like this with a big river.
像這樣坐擁大江的城市真的很少見
Is that a good thing?
那是好事嗎？
What?
什麼？
So do you think that's a good thing or a bad thing?
所以你認為那是好事還是壞事？
Of course that's good
當然好啊
I think Xiaotiao River is better
我覺得小條的江比較好
Feeling both elegant and charming
感覺既優雅又旖旎
But I think Director Goo prefers Dae Jiang.
但我想具理事應該比較喜歡大江
Isn’t the person you like Director Goo?
你喜歡的人不是具理事嗎？
Growing up, was there anyone you wanted to emulate?
從小到大有哪個人 是你想仿效的對象嗎？
What to imitate?
仿效的對象？
It’s just that you want to be like that person
就是你想變成像那個人一樣
Maybe not
好像沒有
i have had
我曾經有過
When I first started working in public relations
剛開始從事公關工作時
I knew nothing about this field so I did a lot of research
我對這個領域一無所知 所以做了很多研究
Suddenly someone caught my eye
突然間有個人吸引住我的視線
She started out as a reporter in South Korea
她在韓國一開始是當記者
Later, he moved to the portal website to do public relations.
後來轉戰到入口網站做公關
She also served as the head of public relations during the U.S. presidential election
她在美國總統大選中 也是擔任公關負責人
He also worked in a consulting company related to corporate sustainability.
還曾在企業永續 相關諮詢顧問公司工作過
Yes, it's her
沒錯，就是她
When I heard the person you like is Director Goo
當我聽到你喜歡的人是具理事
I felt like you do now
我那時的感受就像你現在這樣
But what can be done? that's the fact
但又能怎麼樣呢？事實就是如此
She is someone I can't surpass
她是我無法超越的人
I really hope you will have good results
我真心希望你們會有好結果
Xiao Zhao! Xiaomin!
小昭！小旻！
Well, here it is!
嗯，在這裡！
Yes, I am Xu Dongxun
對，我是徐東訓
Today is Saturday, what are your plans?
今天是星期六，你有什麼計畫？
Well, I don’t have any special plans.
這個嘛，沒什麼特別的計畫
So can you spare some time for me?
那你能抽點時間給我嗎？
What?
什麼？
You said there's nothing left to do
你都說沒什麼事要做了
Of course office workers cannot spend their golden weekend in such an empty way.
上班族的黃金週末 當然不能過得那麼空虛
So how do I get through it?
那我該怎麼度過？
Let's meet first
我們先見面吧
- That way you'll know - Thanks
- 那樣你就會知道 - 謝謝
How to spend a perfect Saturday
如何完美度過星期六的方法
OK, I will look forward to it
好啊，我會好好期待的
Okay, I'll pass you the location
好，我把地點傳給你
within one hour
一小時內
goodbye
再見
Hey, it seems I have to go
喂，我似乎得走了
I closed all the shops just to come here.
我為了過來把店都關了
Feel sorry
抱歉
Is it Representative Xu?
是徐代表嗎？
Did Xiao Meng eavesdrop on our conversation at the pig's trotter shop ?
小孟那時在豬腳店 有偷聽我們說話吧？
right
對
It seems like it's going to spread throughout the company.
看來要傳遍全公司了
No wonder everyone says you shouldn’t make appointments to meet near the company
難怪大家都說不該約在公司附近見面
What? Are you going on a date?
什麼？你要去約會？
Is this the kind of date I know?
是我認知的那種約會？
I am leaving
我走了
What's the situation now?
現在是什麼情況？
You were rejected and she went on a date?
你被人拒絕，她卻跑去約會？
Yun Zhao didn’t know I was rejected
允昭不知道我被拒絕了
Why don't you tell her?
你為什麼不告訴她？
Why tell her?
幹嘛跟她說？
Said that I felt lonely and uncomfortable after being rejected
說我被拒之後寂寞又難受
Do you want her to comfort me?
要她安慰我嗎？
That's the real scum, right?
那樣才是真正的人渣吧？
That's true
那倒是
cheers
乾杯
(Room 1)
（一號房）
alright…
好了…
Stop fighting
別再打了
what? Why?
幹嘛？為什麼？
It's been 30 minutes, let's go
已經30分鐘了，走吧
Then we still have 30 minutes
那我們還有30分鐘啊
Because it hurts me to hear
因為我聽得有點痛苦
The same drumming sound for 30 minutes
整整30分鐘都是一樣的敲鼓聲
That's why I asked you to wait somewhere else.
所以我才叫你去別的地方等啊
You insisted on coming here
是你堅持要過來的
Because I didn't know your strength was so bad
因為我不知道你的實力這麼糟糕
Hey, beginners are all like this...
喂，初學者都是這樣…
gone
走了
OK
好啦
How many interests do you have?
你到底有幾種興趣啊？
Do you have time to work like this?
這樣有時間工作嗎？
Really
真是的
She's such a weirdo
她真是個怪人
Why does she have to come to me to get nervous on the weekend?
她幹嘛偏要在週末來找我發神經啊？
No matter how interested I am, it's not her turn to take care of it.
就算我的興趣再多，也輪不到她管
You just let her go like that?
你就那樣讓她走了？
That kid came all the way to find you.
那孩子大老遠跑去找你耶
yes
是啊
Why don't you take her to have something to eat?
你好歹帶她去吃點東西吧
I'm very cautious
我很小心翼翼
Afraid that if she is not careful, she will become
怕一個不小心她會變得
Hate me even more
更討厭我
what is her name?
她叫什麼名字？
An Yuzhen
安俞真
- How come you don't even know her name? - Yu Zhen, okay
- 你怎麼連她的名字都不知道？ - 俞真，好
You come back to Korea this time
你這次回來韓國
One of the reasons should be to repair the relationship with her, right?
其中一個原因 應該是想跟她修復好關係吧？
That's the main reason
那才是最主要的原因
It’s really hard. Let’s have a drink.
真的太難了，乾一杯吧
It's definitely not easy
肯定不容易啊
but seriously
但說真的
in my opinion
依我看來
As long as you can be candid, you'll be fine
只要你能坦率一點就沒事了
If she really hates you that much, I think she...
要是她真的那麼討厭你，我想她…
I mean Yu Zhen
我是說俞真
She won't go to the company to find you either
她也不會跑去公司找你
- Really? - so
- 真的嗎？ - 所以
You might as well tell her what's on your mind honestly.
你乾脆老實地對她說出心裡話吧
"Actually, I don't know what to do
“其實我不知道該怎麼做才好
please tell me
拜託你告訴我
I really want to get along well with you."
我真的很想跟你好好相處”
something like this
類似這樣
What if I say I want to get along with her and she tells me to go away?
萬一我說想跟她好好相處 她卻叫我滾開，那該怎麼辦？
Then just do it, what else?
那你就照做啊，不然呢？
Hey, who cares if you are her mother or who you are?
喂，管你是她媽還是誰
If she doesn't like it, you can just get out of here.
要是她不樂意，你也只能乖乖滾開啊
not me…
不是，我…
I am her mother, but except for her mobile phone number, I know little about everything else.
我是她媽媽，但除了手機號碼 其他的我都一知半解
I know nothing about her, am I worthy of being her mother?
我對她一無所知，還配當她媽嗎？
Why don't you go see your ex-husband?
你怎麼不去見你前夫一面？
As long as you don't want to grab a knife as soon as you meet
只要你們不是一見面就想拿刀
The relationship between each other
互砍對方的關係
- Yun Zhao! - What?
- 允昭！ - 什麼？
Yun Zhao, do you know Park Yun Zhao?
允昭，你認識朴允昭吧？
Agent Park Yoon-so from your company’s PR team 3
你們公司公關三組的朴允昭代理
What?
什麼？
How do you know her?
你怎麼會認識她？
She is the person I took care of at Cao Ya Public Relations
她是我在曹亞公關帶過的人
Hey, please take good care of our Yun Zhao
喂，拜託你好好照顧我們允昭
She's a really nice person
她真的是個很不錯的人
I really love her and love her, please.
我真的很疼她又很喜愛她，拜託你了
Why is this world so small?
這世界怎麼這麼小啊？
So you don’t know? small enough
原來你不知道啊？有夠小的
The world is as small as a culture pot full of bean sprouts
這世界像種滿豆芽的培養盆一樣小
- I suddenly want to eat bean sprouts - What?
- 突然想吃豆芽了 - 什麼？
Some demand-side platforms
有些需求方平臺
Will utilize both third-party data and first-party data
會同時活用第三方數據及第一方數據
Some will only use one type of data
有些則只會使用其中一種數據
But as you can see so far...
但就像各位目前所看到的…
A refresher course for current public relations professionals?
現職公關人員的進修課程？
When did you start getting involved?
你從何時開始參與的？
I'll tell you later
我待會再告訴你
Because now it’s me on stage to deliver the speech
因為現在換我上臺發表了
(Programmatic advertising in the metaverse)
（元宇宙裡的程序化廣告）
Okay, let’s continue the speech of Minister Kim Joo-yeon.
好的，接續金珠研部長的演說
Next, I want to explain programmatic advertising in the metaverse.
我接下來要針對元宇宙裡的 程序化廣告進行說明
Please see
請看
The demand-side platform data management platform and supply-side platform mentioned by Minister Jin just now
剛才金部長所提及的需求方平臺 數據管理平臺及供應方平臺
How will it be presented in the metaverse in the form of advertising...
將如何以廣告形式去呈現在元宇宙…
so for you
所以對你而言
This is the perfect way to spend a Saturday
這就是完美度過星期六的方式啊
I thought you would like it too
我以為你也會喜歡呢
Yes, I like it very much
對，我很喜歡
you really know me
你真的很了解我
What do you think after listening to the course?
你聽完課程有什麼感想？
Everyone is really amazing
大家真的很了不起
I'm busy enough just with work , but I still find time to study these things
光是應付工作就夠忙了 竟然還能抽空去研究這些東西
It's so hard to make a living
想混口飯吃就是這麼不容易
Industries are changing rapidly these days
這年頭各行業變化迅速
If you don’t enrich yourself, it will be difficult to keep up.
如果不充實自己是很難跟上的
you are right
你說得沒錯
The media environment is always changing at a dizzying pace
媒體環境的變化 總是快得令人眼花撩亂
So do you want to join us next time?
那你下次要不要一起參與？
me?
我嗎？
Oh, forget it
唉唷，算了吧
I still have a lot to be desired
我還有很多不足之處
what you mean?
你指的是什麼？
I'm grateful that you always give me courage
我很感謝你總是帶給我勇氣
But now is not the time
但現在還不是時候
I know this very well
這點我很有自知之明
To be honest, I really want to participate
老實說，我的確很想參與
If we study together, we can understand more deeply
如果一起學習，就能了解得更深入
It can also expand your network of contacts
也能拓展人脈
But now I want to focus on the world
但我現在想把精力專注在世容上
I'm afraid that once I get involved, I want to do this well but also take care of that.
我怕我一旦投入其中 既想做好這個，又想兼顧那個
In the end, he ended up with nothing.
結果卻落得兩頭空的下場
I know exactly where my abilities are
我很清楚我的能力到哪裡
OK, I can understand
好，我能理解
I seem to be putting pressure on you invisibly
我好像無形中給你壓力了
When the time is right, you can tell me again.
等時機恰當，你再跟我說吧
Then we can do it together
到時再一起做就行了
Representative Xu, you are a very good person
徐代表，你是個很好的人
Because of this, I think I should make it clear to you
正因如此，我想我更該跟你說清楚
I don't feel that way about you the way you feel about me.
我還不像你喜歡我那樣 對你有那種感覺
Although you are a good person
雖然你是個好人
But it hasn’t given me the idea of ​​dating yet
但還沒有讓我產生想交往的念頭
besides…
還有…
I agreed to date you just to get over someone
我是為了盡快忘掉某人 才答應跟你約會的
You might think it's selfish but it's the most effective way
你可能會認為這麼做很自私 但這是最有效的方法
So even if you're disappointed in me and refuse to continue dating me
所以就算你對我感到失望 拒絕繼續跟我約會
- I can accept it calmly... - I still feel very lucky
- 我也能坦然接… - 我還是覺得很慶幸
At least your reasons aren't the same as refusing a refresher course.
至少你的理由不像拒絕進修課程那樣
Say you're not ready yet
說你還沒準備好
It’s best to forget as soon as possible
能盡快遺忘是最好的
if you want to forget
如果你想忘掉的話
Everyone, have you seen how popular intranet message boards are with bullshit chats nowadays?
各位，你們有看到現在內聯網留言板 跟胡扯瞎聊有多熱絡嗎？
Everyone said that the server crashed in the middle of the meeting, which is Shi Yong's usual style.
大家都說開會開到一半伺服器當機 不愧是世容一貫的風格
No, I'm not talking about that
不是，我不是說那個
There is a lot of interest in the internal culture improvement program and looking forward to future developments
有很多人對內部文化改善計畫 產生興趣並期待未來的發展
Some people also asked when the survey will be conducted
也有人問問卷調查何時要進行
It seems that the server crash has attracted more attention.
看來伺服器當機反而引來更多的關心
But why didn’t Agent Park, the original planner of Sexiang, say a word?
不過世想的原策畫人朴代理 怎麼一句話都沒說？
She should be the happiest person
她應該是最開心的人吧
Is it necessary to do this?
一定要這樣做嗎？
Is there no other way?
沒有其他方法了嗎？
Yes, we must use negative marketing methods
對，我們一定要採取 負面行銷的方式進行
Negative marketing?
負面行銷？
Did you know that recently on the market, only products containing protein powder are
你知道最近市面上 只要是含有蛋白粉的成品
Will they all be popular?
都會大受歡迎吧？
Like high-protein bread or high-protein nutrition bars
像是高蛋白麵包或高蛋白營養棒
But can you trust the ingredients added to those finished products?
但你信得過那些成品添加的成分嗎？
No one can guarantee
誰也無法保證
But our finished products only use raw materials approved by the Food and Drug Administration
但我們的成品只使用 食藥處認可的原料
Chi Hyo
智孝
Let those athletes and Internet celebrities with large subscriptions to audio and video platforms
讓那些影音平臺 訂閱數眾多的運動選手和網紅
talk about the topic in a roundabout way
以迂迴的方式談論這個話題
We also manipulate social media comments
我們也會操縱社群媒體的留言
These are all written in the plan, you just need to open it and read it.
這些都寫在企劃書裡了 你只要翻開來看就好
Is that difficult to understand?
那些內容很難理解嗎？
It's not that I can't understand
我不是無法理解
But if we use negative marketing techniques to criticize other people’s products
但如果我們用負面行銷手法 去抨擊別人的產品
Small manufacturers will suffer a huge blow
那小型廠商會蒙受巨大的打擊
so what?
所以呢？
Those things have nothing to do with you
那些事都跟你無關啊
Are you opposed to high-protein bread?
你是因為高蛋白麵包才反對的吧？
Because that bakery was the client you were responsible for before joining Seyong
因為那家麵包店 是你進入世容之前負責的客戶
Are you worried that they won't be able to hold on?
你擔心他們撐不住
But that's your private emotion, right?
但那是你的私人情感吧？
You still give me the feeling that you were Agent Park during the agency period.
你給我的感覺依舊是 代理商時期的朴代理
It sounds like negative marketing at best , but it’s basically...
說好聽點是負面行銷 但這根本就是…
Does Team Leader Chi know about this?
池組長知道這件事嗎？
Could she be unaware?
難道她會不知情嗎？
I have already reported these contents to her.
這些內容我都已經向她報告過了
The third-party manufacturer will come over for a meeting today
協力廠商今天會過來開會
Team Leader Chi agrees to carry out this project?
池組長同意進行這個企劃案？
Since this case is ongoing , it means she agrees.
既然這案子是進行式 那就代表她同意啦
The manufacturer's people are here
廠商的人來了
Seems like someone you know well
似乎是你熟識的人
(Cao Ya)
（曹亞）
Miss Li Shizhang, this way please
李世掌小姐，這邊請
- Yes, how are you doing? - Hello
- 是，你過得好嗎？ - 你好
world palm
世掌
(eCao Ya PR, representative, Li Shizhang)
（e曹亞公關，代表，李世掌）
I opened a small agency
我開了一間小型代理商
Specialized in managing messages on digital media platforms
專門管理數位媒體平臺的留言
Comments and influencers
評論及網紅
Why didn't you tell me? I do not even know
你怎麼沒跟我說？我都不知道
So how did Jihyo find you?
那智孝是怎麼找上你的？
that
那個
She said it was difficult to write off expenses through normal channels in this case.
她說這件案子很難經由 正常管道核銷費用
Payment must be made through subcontractors
得透過分包商來進行支付
She saw my name while searching for agents and called me.
她在搜尋代理商時 看見我的名字就打給我了
Of course I'm grateful
我當然很感激啊
-Shizhang- Yes, I know
- 世掌 - 對，我知道
That high-protein bakery was once a client of Cao Ya Public Relations
那家高蛋白麵包店 曾經是曹亞公關的客戶
That store is now managed by CEO Kim Hee-young through Global Communications.
那間店現在由金熙英代表 透過環球傳播在負責
So I have to hide it from her
所以得瞞著她才行
Even if she doesn't know it was you , she will know that it was Shi Yong who did it.
就算她不知道是你做的 但她也會知道是世容在搞鬼
It's my job to make sure she doesn't find out
我的工作就是要確保她不會發現
But it's wrong to do this
但這樣做是不對的
Director Park
朴室長
please let me go
求你放過我吧
Just don't worry about it, okay?
你就不要計較了，好嗎？
Do you know how much it costs to have a nanny to take care of twins?
你知道請褓姆照顧雙胞胎 要花多少錢嗎？
Yun Zhao, I understand, I can understand your mood
允昭，我明白，我能理解你的心情
But I have to do everything
但我什麼都得做
What's more, this is Se Yong's case
更何況這是世容的案子
If I handle it well, I might be able to get other cases.
要是我處理得好 說不定還能拿到其他案子
No matter what, I have to survive
無論如何，我都要存活下來
Just open one eye or close one eye.
你就睜一隻眼，閉一隻眼吧
You are Jihyo’s boss
你是智孝的上司
If you don't agree, the matter may fall through
如果你不同意，這件事就可能會泡湯
I can't let that happen
我不能讓那種事發生
So just do me this favor, okay?
所以你就幫我這個忙嘛，好嗎？
two sets
二組
What is the largest event in the biopharmaceutical industry ?
生物製藥業界裡 最大規模的盛會是什麼？
It's the J.P. Morgan Annual Meeting
就是摩根大通年會
Right? That's right
對吧？沒錯
That's held every year in San Francisco
那每年都會在舊金山舉行
The Public Relations Office will also send two people to participate every year
公關室每年也會派兩位人員參加
You also know this, right?
這你們也知道吧？
One team leader, one team member
一位組長，一位組員
Is it up to you to participate this year?
今年是由你去參加嗎？
It's almost like a vacation
那簡直跟度假沒兩樣
I'm here to work, you brat.
我是去工作的，臭小子
Of course, that's work
當然了，那是工作
that
那個
Our second group this time...
我們二組這次…
Help me score
幫我配樂
Seung Hee, do you want to go?
勝熙，你想去嗎？
me? Really?
我嗎？真的嗎？
Leader Song, I will be loyal to you!
宋組長，我會對你效忠的！
Oh my God
唉唷，天啊
Is this the army?
這裡是軍隊嗎？
She is too excited
她也太興奮了
Lee Seung Hee is sure to get an A this time
李勝熙這次準拿A
Are you sure that's the case?
你確定是那樣嗎？
Didn’t you also go there after you were promoted to agent?
你不也是升上代理之後去的嗎？
- Oh, yeah. - Yeah.
- 喔，對耶 - 是啊
I also went there after I was promoted to section chief.
我也是升上科長才去的
So Lee Seung Hee will definitely get an A this time
所以李勝熙這次一定會拿A
Will be promoted to agent smoothly
還會順利升上代理
no doubt
毫無疑問
Li Shengxi
李勝熙
Congratulations in advance
提前恭喜你囉
(The day for promotion has finally arrived...)
（升遷的日子終於到來了…）
- What's the next sentence? - Xiao Meng
- 下一句是什麼？ - 小孟
Are you here to play in the company?
你是來公司玩的嗎？
no
不是
That kid just came to the company to have fun.
那小子簡直是來公司玩的
(expected date of delivery)
（預產期）
Come to the stairwell
來樓梯間一下
Can't we make an appointment somewhere else?
我們不能約其他地方嗎？
That is to say
就是說啊
You go find somewhere else
你去找別的地方
There aren't even windows here, it's so stuffy.
這裡連窗戶都沒有，悶死人了
It's up to you to find it. You've been around longer than me.
應該由你去找吧 你在世容待得比我久
What do you want to say?
你想說什麼？
Was the date that day not going well?
是那天的約會不怎麼樣嗎？
what?
幹嘛？
The person in charge of the protein powder case in Group 2 is you.
二組負責蛋白粉案子的人是你
Have you read the plan?
你看過企劃書了嗎？
seen it already
看過了
It turns out this isn't the first time this has happened.
原來這種事不是第一次了
What you call negative marketing
你們所謂的負面行銷
Now it's done under the table
現在是在檯面下進行
It was blatant before
以前可是明目張膽呢
This is Shirong’s culture, an outdated system
這就是世容的文化，陳腐過時的制度
Se Yong still has a long way to go
世容還有很長的路要走
Hello
喂
Don't sound like the leader of the internal culture improvement project team.
你別用內部文化 改善計畫組長的口吻說話
tell me what to do
告訴我該怎麼做
Should I warn the manager of a high-protein bakery?
我該警告高蛋白麵包店的店長嗎？
“There will be messages and comments attacking you online , so be prepared in advance.
“網上會出現攻擊你們的 留言跟評論，要提前做好準備
But those are all Se-yong’s tricks behind the scenes.” Is it going to be like this?
不過那些都是世容在暗中搞鬼” 要像這樣嗎？
But as a member of Shirong, I shouldn’t do that
但我身為世容的一員不該那麼做
It's my responsibility, I'm the one in charge
這是我的責任，我是負責人
Then you ask to withdraw from the case and say that you think that is unethical.
那你就要求退出案子 說你認為那樣不合乎道義
It would be even more irresponsible to do that
那麼做更不負責
Besides, what if I'm the only one who quits?
況且只有我退出又如何？
So what do you want?
所以你到底想怎樣？
I want to know too
我也想知道啊
I'm so depressed that I'm going crazy
我鬱悶得快瘋了
And this also involves Li Shizhang
而且這還牽扯到李世掌
What?
什麼？
When did you get pregnant...
你什麼時候懷…
No, that's not what I meant
不是，我不是那個意思
Okay, so...
好，那麼…
Then there's no way
那就沒辦法了
How can I travel far away after just giving birth to a baby?
剛生完小孩哪有辦法出遠門？
Right? You can't go, can you?
對吧？你去不了吧？
right
對
Oh, I see
嗯，知道了
But you got pregnant too quickly...
但你也太快就懷…
No, I mean...
不是，我是說…
Since you are already married, you might as well get pregnant right away
既然你都結婚了，馬上懷孕也好
But aren’t you still under 30?
但你不是還不到30歲嗎？
You guys are really anxious. It seems you can't wait any longer.
你們還真是著急，看來是等不及了
Oh, sorry
喔，抱歉
Well, I'm sorry, I talked too much...
那個，對不起，我說話太…
Yes, now the country is worried that the national birth rate is too low
是啊，現在國家都在擔心 國民的生育率太低
Well done, it's patriotic
做得好，這是愛國的表現
Worthy of awards and encouragement
值得頒獎鼓勵
sorry
對不起
Please send me there next time
請你下次一定要派我去
No problem, next time, okay
沒問題，下次，好
A year from now?
一年後嗎？
that
那個
you plan
你打算
Taking a long maternity leave?
休很長的產假嗎？
I'm not sure about that either.
那個我也不太確定
Yes, how can you predict it? We can only take one step at a time depending on the situation.
也是，你哪有辦法預測？ 只能看狀況走一步算一步
Shall I go out first?
那我先出去囉？
- Okay
- 好的 - 好
By the way, congratulations
對了，恭喜你
Take good care of your body
要好好調養身體
Thanks
謝謝
Hey, I closed the door too loudly
喂，我關門太大聲了
It didn't scare you, did it?
沒有嚇到你吧？
Won't you leave?
你不走嗎？
When I see Shin Ji Hyo now, I want to beat her up, so I need to calm down.
我現在一見到申智孝就想揍她 所以需要冷靜一下
I really don't want to go back to the office
真不想回辦公室
Me too
我也是
(inbox)
（收件匣）
He wrote back
他回信了
(I am in Genzyme)
（我是在健讚體讚）
(The poster who posted the review of Serong Protein Powder)
（發布世容蛋白粉評論的發文者）
Hey, wait a minute
喂，等等
I'm going out in the field
我要出外勤了
good
好
I am leaving
我走了
Thanks for your hard work
辛苦了
Do you really not want to see me succeed?
你就那麼不想看到我成功嗎？
no…
不是…
Please don't say anything to the team leader
拜託你什麼都別對組長說
And don't dispute my case.
也別對我的案子提出異議
- Jihyo- This is my first case
- 智孝 - 這是我的第一件案子
I'll figure it out myself
我會自己看著辦的
My name is Yoo Jae-min
我叫做柳才旻
not just me
不光是我
I bought it after careful research with my friend who works out with me.
我是跟一起運動的朋友 好好研究過才買來喝的
Their skin also has allergic reactions
他們的皮膚也都有過敏反應
Can I confirm it?
我可以確認看看嗎？
I heard the formula has been upgraded
我聽說配方有升級
The ingredients are different from before
成分變得跟之前不一樣
I mean it becomes worse
我是說變得比較不好
but
不過
Are you really an employee of Serong?
你真的是世容的員工嗎？
I've called several times before
我之前也打過幾次電話
But you all insist that there is nothing wrong with the product
但你們都堅稱產品沒有問題
Who did you talk to on the phone?
你是跟哪位通電話的？
I called Shi Rong directly and they immediately transferred me to the person in charge.
我直接打去世容 他們就馬上幫我轉接負責人
There was a man who said he was the person in charge of protein powder.
有個男的說他是蛋白粉的負責人
- Is that person named Meng... - By the way
- 那個人是不是叫孟… - 對了
What's it called there? This is where the ingredients are tested
那裡叫什麼？就是檢驗成分的地方
Food and Drug Administration?
食藥處嗎？
Yes, that's right there
對，就是那裡
He also sent me the inspection report there and told me there was nothing abnormal.
他還寄了那裡的檢驗報告給我 跟我說沒有異常
That’s why I get so angry and post everywhere
所以我才會一肚子火，到處上傳貼文
(Lawyer, Ahn Eun-seok)
（律師，安恩錫）
Your secretary told me you haven't gotten off work yet
你的祕書跟我說你還沒下班
(KA Law Firm, lawyer, Ahn Eun-seok)
（KA律師事務所，律師，安恩錫）
Looks like it's time to fire her
看來該解僱她了
Why fire her for such a trivial matter?
何必為這種小事解僱她？
I don't need a secretary who can't accurately judge the boss's needs.
我不需要一個無法準確判斷 上司需求的祕書
It’s not like you want to engage in politics with her anyway
反正你又不是要跟她搞政治
I heard about it
我聽說了
you were nominated
你被提名了
Preparing for party primaries
正在準備黨內初選
Are you here to talk about my political career?
你是來談我的政治生涯的嗎？
I feel like you have something to ask me for
感覺你有事要拜託我
The way guests are treated here is really cold.
這裡的待客方式還真冷漠
Just focus on the key points
講重點就好
Yu Zhen
俞真
I want to discuss Yu Zhen's matter with you
我想跟你商量俞真的事
What to discuss?
要商量什麼？
how? Doesn't she answer your call?
怎麼？她不接你電話嗎？
Are things not going your way?
事情不如你所願嗎？
It seems I guessed it right
看來我猜對了
- You seem happy - Yeah
- 你好像很開心 - 是啊
I'm very happy, so happy
我很開心，超痛快的
But what a pity
不過真遺憾
I have nothing to say
我沒什麼好說的
I won’t discuss anything related to Yu Zhen with you either.
也不會跟你商量任何有關俞真的事
I already knew you would do this , why did you come all the way?
我早就知道你會這樣 幹嘛還特地跑來啊？
Don't wear that tie in front of the campaign team
在競選團隊面前不要繫那條領帶
It gives people the feeling of trying to pretend to be young
會給人一種想拼命裝年輕的感覺
(Se Yong)
（世容）
This site is Hapjeong Station
本站是合井站
Our representatives are very humorous.
我們代表本來就很幽默
That was just a joke, how could...
那只是開玩笑，怎麼能…
- Yes, I am Yoo Jae-min. - That was just a joke.
- 是，我是柳才旻 - 那只是玩笑話而已
There's no need to call the director for this kind of thing, right?
這種事沒必要打給局長吧
- are you free? - She has no political stance
- 你不忙嗎？ - 她沒有任何政治立場
- As far as I know, that's it. - Why did you call the director?
- 據我所知是這樣 - 幹嘛還打給局長啊？
Hello?
喂？
- I guess it means nothing else. - Yeah.
- 我想那沒有其他意思 - 對
- I'll call you later... - Please wait.
- 我晚點再打給… - 請稍等
I'll call you later
我晚點打給你
What are you doing? Where did Xiao Meng and Hou Ji go? Didn't they come to work?
搞什麼？小孟跟厚佶去哪了？ 他們沒來上班嗎？
They seemed to have had a dinner with the reporters responsible for Se Yong yesterday.
他們昨天好像跟負責世容的 記者們去聚餐了
What about you? Why didn't you go?
那你們呢？你們怎麼沒去？
talk
說啊
Because I have something to do
因為我有點事
I'm going crazy, really, this brat
我要瘋了，真是的，這個臭小子
Yes, Reporter Kim
是，金記者
(Is she crazy? She actually used soy flour as a metaphor for a presidential candidate?)
（她是不是瘋了？她居然用黃豆粉 來比喻總統候選人？）
(She should have thought about the consequences before posting this kind of post here , otherwise it would be even more ridiculous)
（她在這上傳這種貼文之前 應該想過結果吧，沒有的話更荒唐）
represent
代表
Well, what's the matter?
嗯，什麼事？
The other party is the presidential candidate of the opposition party
對方是在野黨的總統候選人
How can you mention soy flour?
你怎麼能提到黃豆粉呢？
(#Oh my God, it’s soybean flour # If you want to eat it, you should eat it in moderation)
（#天啊，是黃豆粉 #想吃也該適可而止）
Yes, now we have to talk to the people at the Democratic Party headquarters
是，現在要跟位於民心黨黨部的
- Reporter Jin Minzhi online - That’s great
- 金敏芝記者連線 - 真好
The incident caused public concern
因本次事件造成民眾的擔憂
- As a party representative... - Oh, take a picture for me
- 身為黨代表的我… - 喔，幫我拍張照
- what? - hurry up
- 幹嘛？ - 快點
The Party’s Ethics Committee and Emergency Response Committee
黨內的倫理委員會及緊急對策委員會
look here
看這邊
Relevant persons will be thoroughly investigated and appropriate...
將會對相關人士 徹底進行調查及適當的…
For justice…
為了伸張正義…
- I hereby promise all citizens... - Hey, look...
- 我在此答應各位國民… - 喂，你看…
Party representative’s formal apology
黨代表這番正式的道歉
- Very good - I'm afraid it still can't calm the people's anger...
- 很好 - 恐怕仍無法平息國民的…
(#久久的吃Out #The roasted pork rinds in memory)
（#久違的外出吃飯 #記憶中的烤豬皮）
(#Michelin gourmet restaurant, tastes great # Drinking soju is the truth)
（#米其林美食餐廳，味道超棒 #喝燒酒才是真理）
(#Oh my God, it’s soybean flour # If you want to eat it, you should eat it in moderation)
（#天啊，是黃豆粉 #想吃也該適可而止）
So what if you should eat roasted pork rinds with soybean flour ?
吃烤豬皮就該配黃豆粉 那又怎麼了？
represent
代表
Is it necessary to over-interpret a social media post ?
不過是一則社群媒體貼文 有必要過度解讀嗎？
I just felt it at that time
我那時只是有感而發
Am I not allowed to express my thoughts?
難道我不能表達想法嗎？
Isn’t the Republic of Korea a liberal country?
大韓民國不是自由主義國家嗎？
If this were not Korea, I would suggest you
如果這裡不是韓國，我就會建議你
Don't belittle your opponent in this way
別以這種方式貶低對手
Just actively support the candidate you like
只要積極支持喜歡的候選人就好
That way it will look more stylish
那樣看起來才會更有格調
But this is Korea
但這裡是韓國
Koreans are extremely sensitive to political overtones
韓國人對政治色彩極為敏感
Although your social media is your personal space , it also represents the world.
雖然你的社群媒體是你的私人空間 但它同時也代表著世容
Those who support opposition party candidates
那些支持在野黨候選人的群眾
We are already planning to boycott Serong’s brand.
已經開始醞釀要抵制世容的品牌了
If you are still stubborn
如果你還是固執己見
Then just stop running social media.
那乾脆別經營社群媒體了
The risk is too great
風險太大了
Everyone is too sensitive
大家未免也太敏感了
One post can make a fuss
一則貼文也能大驚小怪
If the risk posed by the business owner causes the stock price to fall
要是企業主帶來的風險害股價下跌
It will be more difficult to secure the representative’s seat
代表的位子會更難保
Do you think the vice president will sit back and do nothing?
你覺得副社長會坐視不管嗎？
Okay, got it
好啦，知道了
cheer up
振作一點
So
那麼
Could you please clean up the mess?
麻煩你們收拾殘局了
OK
好的
What to do now?
這下該怎麼辦？
It can only end with accidental events
只能以偶發事件作結了
They must also be prepared to clarify reports that the move has no political implications.
還得準備澄清報導 說明該舉動並無政治意味
Director Gu
具理事
Didn’t the representative go to a restaurant at that time?
代表當時不是去了一間餐廳嗎？
It would be better if a few reports about that restaurant could be published
如果能發表幾篇 那間餐廳的相關報導會更好
“A barbecue restaurant that even the second generation of rich people will visit
“連富二代都會光顧的烤肉店
That roasted pork rind is really delicious”
那家烤豬皮真是人間美味”
Okay, let's do this
好，就這麼辦
Connect these two paragraphs
把這兩段做連結
And then add a little bit more relevance here...
然後這裡再添加一點關聯性…
- I looked for the photo, here it is... - Yeah
- 我找過照片了，這裡… - 嗯
That's not what you call a fancy restaurant
那不是所謂的高級餐廳
If reporters ask tough questions
要是記者們丟出尖銳的問題
It would be better to emphasize that it was just an incident
強調那只是偶發事件會比較好
Sorry, I have no way of knowing that kind of thing
抱歉，那種事我無從得知
Oh, Agent Kim
唉唷，金代理
The coffee tastes really good
咖啡還真香呢
- Does that taste good? - not bad
- 那個好喝嗎？ - 還不錯
The suit looks very nice. Did you buy it new?
西裝挺好看的，新買的嗎？
I was wearing this suit to see how little you care about me
我原本就穿這套，看你多不關心我
Hello, first time meeting
你好，初次見面
Hello
你好
- Hi, I am Kim Hoo-gil from Se Yong Public Relations Team 2 - Yes
- 嗨，我是世容公關二組的金厚佶 - 是
You're here
你來啦
I want to talk to you about that
我想跟你談談那件事
Our company also has its own position. Please help us write a favorable report.
我們公司也有自己的立場 請幫忙寫篇有利的報導
- Oh my god, Reporter Kwon - Oh, Agent Kim
- 天啊，權記者 - 喔，金代理
Reporter Goo, how are you doing?
具記者，近來好嗎？
What's going on with Representative Lin?
林代表是怎麼回事啊？
As long as you show your respect this time, I will provide you with better materials.
只要你這次高抬貴手 我會提供更好的素材給你
Okay, three, two, one, start
好，三，二，一，開始
Yes, hello everyone
是，大家好
- We are the "Come for a meal show!" " - show!
- 我們是《來吃一頓飯秀！》 - 秀！
We're going live today with special guests
我們今天要跟特別來賓們 一起進行直播
Come, please introduce yourself
來，請自我介紹
- Hi, I am Xiaolan from Blue Eater Diary - Welcome Xiaolan
- 嗨，我是藍色吃播日記的小藍 - 歡迎小藍
Okay, there are cameras over there too
好，那邊也有攝影機
- Hello everyone! - Say hello
- 大家好！ - 打個招呼吧
Come on, cover both the front and back with soybean flour
來，前後都要沾滿黃豆粉
That's the key to deliciousness
這就是美味的關鍵
Boss, is this the most important step?
老闆，這步驟最重要吧？
- Please be quiet - Okay
- 請保持安靜 - 好
Looks super delicious
看起來超好吃
Come
來
Is it delicious?
很好吃吧？
taste different
味道不一樣
- They did take a good shot. - Not bad, right?
- 他們確實拍得很好 - 不錯吧？
What does this smell like?
這是什麼味道？
- When was this taken? - I know that producer very well.
- 這是什麼時候拍的？ - 我跟那位製作人很熟
Judging from the comments, the response has been pretty good.
從留言看來，反應還不錯
Boss, please pack it for me
老闆，麻煩幫我打包
Thanks to us, their business should be doing great
多虧我們，他們的生意應該會變很好
- Really - That restaurant was already very popular.
- 真是的 - 那間餐廳本來就很紅了
- Maybe it will be better - You're back
- 說不定會更好 - 你回來啦
you are back
你回來啦
(A famous roasted pork rind restaurant that even CEO Se Yong Lim Ji-hyun is obsessed with)
（連世容林知賢代表 都迷上的烤豬皮名店）
It's not bad. The report is well written.
挺不賴的，報導寫得很好呢
Reporter Park was very helpful.
朴記者幫了大忙
- Thank you for your hard work - Really well written
- 辛苦你了 - 真的寫得很棒
- I picked this photo. - Thank you for your hard work.
- 這張照片是我挑的 - 辛苦了
- Hey, thank you for your hard work
- 喂，辛苦了 - 真的辛苦你了
- Thank you for your hard work - No, you have worked harder.
- 辛苦了 - 沒有啦，你比較辛苦
Director Gu
具理事
I see you handled the aftermath very quickly this time.
我看你們這次善後得非常迅速
In my impression, the public relations team of Shiyong
在我印象中，世容公關組
Never been handled so quickly like this time
從未像這次一樣處理得如此快速
Yeah?
是嗎？
What do you want to say?
你想說什麼？
I'm thinking that this incident was caused by the vacancy of the head of the Strategy Headquarters.
我在想這次的事端是因為 策略本部長的空缺所導致的
No one can play coaching chess next to the representative
沒有人能在代表身邊下指導棋
I will look forward to the results of the internal culture improvement plan
我會好好期待 內部文化改善計畫的成果
(Se Yong)
（世容）
I finally woke up
我終於酒醒了
Did he run out again?
他又跑出去了吧？
Is his body made of iron?
他的身體是鐵打的嗎？
How can I keep drinking?
怎麼有辦法喝個不停？
elder brother
哥
Have you ever received complaints about protein powder?
你有收過關於蛋白粉的投訴嗎？
I also sent the ingredients inspection report from the Food and Drug Administration to the other party.
還把食藥處的成分檢驗報告寄給對方
No
沒有啊
Yeah?
是嗎？
yes
對啊
May I ask where Miss Li Shengxi sits?
請問李勝熙小姐坐哪裡？
here
這裡
- Thank you, bye. - Okay, please walk slowly.
- 謝謝，再見 - 好，請慢走
what? Is today her birthday?
什麼啊？今天是她生日嗎？
Brother, you can't just look at other people's cards
哥，你不能隨便看別人的卡片
(Seunghee, congratulations on your pregnancy!)
（勝熙，恭喜你懷孕！）
(Are we going to be aunties?)
（我們要當阿姨了嗎？）
Seung Hee seems to be pregnant
勝熙好像懷孕了
What?
什麼？
This was sent by her friend to congratulate her on her pregnancy.
這是她朋友送來恭喜她懷孕的
- Really? - yes
- 真的嗎？ - 對啊
Seung Hee, you...
勝熙，你…
Don't say anything, and don't congratulate me.
什麼話都別說，也不准恭喜我
Why?
為什麼？
We need to quickly formulate questionnaire questions and send them to all employees
我們得趕緊制定問卷題目 然後發給全體員工
This way we can make plans early
這樣才能早點制定方案
I can't go to San Francisco
我無法去舊金山了
Because the date overlaps with my due date
因為日期跟我的預產期重疊
I may not be able to be promoted to an agent.
我可能也升不上代理了
Who would promote someone who is about to take maternity leave?
誰會讓即將請產假的人升遷啊？
so
所以
us
我們
Let’s hold a meeting as soon as possible
盡快召開會議吧
Well, no problem
嗯，沒問題
I think the questionnaire must be able to assess both objectivity and relativity
我認為問卷必須能同時評估 客觀性及相對性
When we break the problem down into fact-finding
當我們把問題分成實況調查
When thinking about likeability surveys
和喜好度調查去想時
You will find that even multiple choice questions are not enough...
就會發現即便是選擇題也不足以…
Relationship and communication with immediate superiors
與直屬上司間的關係及溝通
Also very important…
也非常重要…
That might be a problem between the group members.
那可能是同組組員之間的問題
Or other team members…
或是其他組員…
The relationship between the team leader and team members is very important
組長跟組員之間的關係很重要
Because we don’t really know how to interact with other groups…
因為我們其實不太會跟其他組…
(High protein bread has no flavor at all and I don’t understand why anyone would want to eat it…)
（高蛋白麵包一點味道也沒有 我搞不懂怎麼會有人想吃…）
Hee Jung, you wrote this part a bit like you were joking
希靜，你這部分寫得有點像在開玩笑
The point is to be a little more aggressive, okay?
重點是要再更具攻擊性一點 明白嗎？
Joo Eun and Jae Hyuk, are you writing smoothly?
珠恩、宰赫，寫得還順利嗎？
- Jaehyuk, write about your own experience - Yes
- 宰赫，寫你自己的經歷 - 是
No, it’s bad for your health if you write about it
不對，你要寫那對身體很不好
Yes, got it
是，知道了
- Because that's your experience - Okay
- 因為那是你的親身經歷 - 好的
You want to write "The more you eat, the worse your condition becomes."
你要寫“吃得越多，狀況越差”
yes
是
very good
很好
(No matter how much you eat, you will only get fatter...)
（無論怎麼吃都只會變胖…）
(It’s better to eat chicken breast and eggs. Who knows what’s added to it?)
（還是吃雞胸肉跟雞蛋就好 誰知道裡面添加了什麼？）
(Protein is less than 20 grams at all)
（蛋白質根本連20公克都不到）
(How can we trust the protein products on the market?)
（這樣我們要如何相信 市面上充斥的蛋白質產品？）
(That's all just business strategy)
（那都只是商業策略）
Hi, sisters
嗨，各位姐姐
I'm Lanie
我是蘭妮
Today’s video has nothing to do with sports
今天的影片與運動無關
You've been eating this kind of high-protein bread a lot lately to go with your workouts, right?
最近你們很常吃這種 高蛋白麵包來搭配運動，對吧？
Look
你們看
But what if after in-depth research, you find high-protein products that are easily available on the market?
但萬一深入了解後發現 市面上能輕易取得的高蛋白產品
What should I do if it’s all garbage?
都是垃圾的話該怎麼辦？
Yes, these are the products you commissioned
是，這些都是你委託的產品
It says that the raw materials are imported protein powder.
上頭寫說原料是使用進口的蛋白粉
But is the origin label consistent with the raw materials?
但原產地標示究竟是否跟原料一致
We are unable to confirm
我們無法進行確認
Through this raw material analysis report
經由這份原料分析報告
It can be seen that the raw materials used are far below the standards approved by the Food and Drug Administration.
能看出所使用的原料都遠遠不及 食藥處許可的標準
So are these high-protein breads a bad food?
所以這些高蛋白麵包是不良食品嗎？
It has absolutely no that ingredient, it's just garbage
完全沒有該成分，這簡直就是垃圾
How was the response in the live message area?
即時留言區的反應怎麼樣？
Because those films were so offensive , they got the majority of negative reviews.
因為那些影片極具攻擊性 所以惡評占了大多數
First of all, I think we should distract the public with other issues
首先，我認為應該要以其他議題 來分散大眾的焦點
I also feel that this problem needs to be solved as soon as possible
我也這麼覺得 得盡快解決掉這個問題
- That's right - That...
- 沒錯 - 那個…
Please be responsible for mastering the method of dissemination first
請你先負責掌握散播的方式
As for seniors, you'd better go meet a few representatives first...
至於前輩，你最好先去見幾位代表…
Eating cup noodles doesn’t seem to be a good idea
吃杯麵好像不太好
Should I order something else to eat?
是不是該叫點別的來吃？
Is Representative Kim out of town?
金代表外出了嗎？
She obviously made an appointment with me
她明明跟我約好了
That's why I sit here in her place
所以我才會代替她坐在這裡
You can tell me directly
你可以直接跟我說的
But if I tell you, you won’t come
但說了你就不會來了
We haven't seen each other for a while
我們好一陣子沒見面了
Didn't get a date either
也沒能約會
Because I'm a little busy
因為我有點忙
Is your heart very busy?
是你的心很忙嗎？
Haven't you successfully promoted high-protein bread before?
你之前不是成功推廣過 高蛋白麵包嗎？
It's not in good condition right now
它現在的狀況不太好
It seems like someone is tampering with you behind my back
好像有人在背後動手腳
The current sales situation of high-protein finished products is miserable
現在的高蛋白成品銷售狀況一片慘澹
Representative Kim went out for a countermeasures meeting.
金代表是為了開對策會議才外出的
Countermeasures meeting?
對策會議？
Yes, she convened several manufacturers to hold a countermeasures meeting
對，她召集了幾家廠商要開對策會議
Is the situation really that bad?
情況真的那麼糟糕嗎？
To be honest, it's really miserable
老實說，真的很慘
Because they are all small businesses
因為他們都是小本生意
One of the store managers is currently hospitalized
其中還有一位店長目前住院中
He must have been under a lot of pressure
他應該是承受了不小的壓力
I'll order something else
我點別的東西吧
It's our fault
是我們搞的鬼
those negative comments
那些負面評論
Serong hired subcontractors to do it.
是世容僱用分包商做的
what to do?
該怎麼辦？
(Se Yong)
（世容）
It was Team Leader Song who asked me to do that.
是宋組長叫我那麼做的
Ingredients test report from the Food and Drug Administration
食藥處的成分檢驗報告
He also gave it to me
也是他給我的
But what happened?
但那怎麼了嗎？
(Public Relations, Section Chief Meng Zhejun)
（公關，孟哲俊科長）
Well, brother Zhejun, what's wrong?
嗯，哲俊哥，怎麼了？
Where are you? Why didn't you come to work?
你在哪？怎麼沒來上班？
I'm on vacation today, what's wrong?
我今天休假，怎麼了嗎？
Apparently you haven't heard of it yet
看樣子你還沒聽說
Doesn't Serong have a message board to listen to customers' voices?
世容不是有個 傾聽顧客聲音的留言板嗎？
Something big happened there now
現在那裡出大事了
Some people say they want to expose the inside story of Shirong's bullying.
有人說要揭發世容仗勢欺人的內幕
He also said that the person in charge, Park Yoon-soo,
還說負責人朴允昭
His career was ruined and even his employees fell down.
害他的事業毀於一旦 連員工都倒下了
I want to expose the domineering and oppressive behavior of the big company Se Yong
我要揭發大企業世容 橫行霸道及欺壓的行為
I was in the bakery of a bakery called Ang
我是在一家叫昂的麵包店的烘焙坊
People who make high protein bread
製作高蛋白麵包的人
We have developed various recipes after painstaking research
我們經過嘔心瀝血的研究 開發出各式食譜
Healthy ingredients, taste and protein content
健康的食材、味道及蛋白質含量
We don't do anything carelessly
我們沒有一項馬虎行事
Later, as the number of customers gradually increased, an agent saw our potential.
後來客人漸漸變多 有家代理商看出了我們的潛力
Proposed an online promotion plan to us
向我們提議了線上宣傳方案
Word of mouth via social media really took off for a while
經由社群媒體的口耳相傳 有段時間真的大受歡迎
But starting two weeks ago, our sales suddenly dropped sharply.
但兩週前開始 我們的營業額突然急速下滑
Financial difficulties due to sudden drop in operating income
因為營業收入驟降導致財務發生困難
My friend ended up passing out from the stress.
我朋友最終因壓力過大而昏倒
- Currently in hospital - Hey, wake up.
- 目前正在住院中 - 喂，你醒醒啊
(Conglomerate Seyong...)
（大企業世容…）
Later I learned about recent random malicious attacks on social media
後來我才知道近來在社群媒體 發起的隨機惡意攻擊
It was instigated by the public relations team of a large company, Serong.
是世容這個大企業的公關組所指使的
And the person in charge of such shameless behavior, Miss Park Yun-soo,
而做出這種無恥行徑的 負責人朴允昭小姐
It is the person I mentioned earlier who appreciates us
正是前面我提到的那位因賞識我們
And the person who first proposed to us online promotion
而率先向我們提議線上宣傳的人
I feel deeply betrayed and can't do anything
我深感背叛，什麼也做不了
This thing hit me hard
這件事讓我大受打擊
We can no longer ignore it, Vice President
我們無法再置之不理了，副社長
From the representative's mistake to this incident
從代表犯錯到這件事
Se Yong’s image continues to collapse
世容的形象持續崩壞中
It should be the job of the chief communications officer to prevent this from happening
防止這種事情發生 應是首席公關長的工作
But after the chief public relations officer took office, similar troubles emerged one after another.
但首席公關長上任之後 類似的麻煩反而層出不窮
I can understand that you want to trust Representative Lin and give her a little more time
我能理解你想相信林代表 並給她多一點時間
But Vice President, now is the time to rectify all this.
但副社長，現在是時候導正這一切了
You mean to correct all this?
你說導正這一切？
Fire the chief public relations officer
解僱首席公關長吧
I want to report the big company Serong for trying to monopolize the market.
我要檢舉大企業世容企圖壟斷市場的
Bullying
欺壓行為
is this real?
這是真的嗎？
I ask you if this is true, Agent Park Yun-soo
我問你這是不是事實，朴允昭代理
Yes
是的
Subtitle translation: Chen Yiying
字幕翻譯：陳怡穎